Resume of

Miraj Morshed Chowdhury

C/O: 12-F1, Tower-7, Suvastu Nazar Vally,

Sahajadpur, Vatara, Dhaka.

Cell: 01788665430, 01673734797,

E-mail: mirajmc@gmail.com



CAREER OBJECTIVE

To build a career by serving the best with integrity to the Organization. Achieving a dynamic and challenging job where I can use my technical and interpersonal skills, creativity and above all my learning experience in order to develop my career and as well as to contribute in the welfare of the Organization.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

• Panjeree Publications Limited

Working as Executive- Human Resources

15th September 2019 to Present

Job Responsibilities:

- Preparing monthly salary and overtime.
- ♣ Preparing Festival, Boishakhi & Profit bonus.
- Monitoring employee attendance.
- ♣ Maintaining employee's provident fund.
- ♣ Look after employee's Hospitalization & Marriage benefit.
- ♣ Maintaining exit employees interview, clearance & their final settlement payment.
- Maintain & monitor employee's loan management.
- ♣ Preparing arrear salary/overtime/bonus.
- **♣** Monitoring and preparing ML benefits.
- ♣ Monitoring all kinds of benefit & payment.
- ♣ Dealing with different concern of the company & preparing their salary and payments.
- Maintaining file management.
- **♣** Monitoring Recruitment, Confirmation and Contract extension.
- Policy making & updating.
- Monitoring employees KPI management.
- **♣** Issuing internal memo, letter & certificates.
- Maintaining all the bank related work.
- ♣ Assisting manager for smooth operation & lead the team.
- **♣** Coordinating with management for organization development.

• Kenpark Bangladesh Apparel (Pvt.) Limited

Worked as Executive - HR, Admin & Compliance

25th November 2017 to 14th September 2019.

Job Responsibilities:

- **♣** Recruitment & Selection process.
- **♣** Training & development.
- **♣** Employee engagement program arrangement.
- **♣** Confirmation, promotion, increment, transfer, department change process.
- ♣ Performance evaluation & Yearly increment preparation.
- **↓** Taking disciplinary action (Show cause, warning letter, Suspension, dismissal and termination).
- ♣ Preparing daily attendance & OT report.
- ♣ Preparing daily manpower report & send it to concern department.
- ♣ Preparing daily cadre report.
- Handling internal dispute.
- Lead the inquiry team for dispute settlement and making & submitting report to management.
- ♣ Dealing with Labor court, Bepza & Labor organizations as a zone head.
- ♣ Handling Food & Transport facility of worker, employee and Expat.
- Petty Cash Management.
- Bank related work.
- ♣ Absent report making, conduct absent meeting & sending absent letter.
- → Preparing report & arrange award giving ceremony for best performer, best efficient team, best quality team.
- **♣** Conducting awareness program.
- ♣ Motivational meeting with the leaders for helping them to achieve company goals.
- ♣ Maintaining monthly struck off & resign report & their payment.
- File management
- Lead the team to achieve targets within given timeline.
- ♣ Assisting managers for running the team & organization smoothly.
- ♣ Preparing, checking & updating audit requirements, reports and personal file.
- ♣ Monitoring the organization environment for ensuring compliance.

• Sanmar Properties Limited.

Worked as Lifestyle Consultant- Junior Executive.

18th March 2017 to 18 November 2017.

Job Responsibilities:

- ♣ Dealing with the clients.
- **♣** Visiting projects with the clients.
- ♣ Helping team to achieve targets.

ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS

MASTERS OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION (MBA)

Result : CGPA 3.12 (Out of 4.00)

Major Subject : Human Resource Management

Year of Passing : 2018

University : University of Chittagong

BACHELOR OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION (BBA)

Result : CGPA 3.38 (Out of 4.00)

Major Subject : Human Resource Management

Year of Passing : 2016

University: Premier University, Chittagong

HIGHER SECONDARY CERTIFICATE (HSC)

Result : CGPA 4.10 (Out of 5.00)

Year of Passing : 2010

Group : Business Studies **Name of the Institution** : Mirsarai College

Name of the Board : Chittagong

SECONDARY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE (SSC)

Result : CGPA 4.31 (Out of 5.00)

Year of Passing : 2008
Group : Science

Name of the Institution : Bamon Sunder F.A. High School

Name of the Board : Chittagong

PARTICIPATIONS

- ♣ Seminar on "KPI for Business Performance Analysis" organized by WARD (7th February 2020)
- ♣ Training session organized by Change Associate for 20 Hours on
 - * Communication
 - * Employee harassment in workplace
 - * Building positive & respectful working environment
- → Day long workshop "Supply Chain Management" Organized by Chittagong University, Department of Marketing (April 11, 2015)

SKILLS

Computer Literacy:

Computing: Basic knowledge of Office application i.e., MS Office and other common applications with Internet surfing. Also able to type both Bengali & English with a good speed.

Languages and Communication Skill:

Excellent verbal and writing proficiency in both English and Bengali.

Self-driven, hardworking, change oriented, Positive Attitude, Capacity work under pressure.

Field of Expertise:

*Program Coordinator * Correspondences * Teaching

STRENGTHS

- ➡ Time management & self-discipline
- **♣** Eager to shouldered responsibility & lead from the front.
- **♣** Strong communicating skill
- ♣ Ability of multitasking
- self-development Skill
- Courage and honesty

PERSONAL DETAILS

Father's Name : Nurun Nabi Chowdhury

Mother's Name : Jannat Ara Begum
Nationality : Bangladeshi by Birth

Religion : Islam

Date of Birth : 1st January 1993

Sex : Male
Marital Status : Single

Permanent Address: C/O: Sherazul Islam Chy Bari,

Village: West Mithanala, Ward No # 05,

P/O: Bamon Sundor, Darogerhat, P/S: Mirsarai, Dist: Chittagong.

REFERENCES

1. Mr. Md. Foisal Uddin 2. Dr. Muhammad Mustafizur Rahaman

Director (Admin & Finance) Cheif Revenue Officer (Deputy Secretary)

Fusion Foods Ltd. Chittagong City Corporation.

Rahman Bhaban, Nimtala, Chittagong Anderkilla, Chittagong

Contact No: 01847-188702 Contact No: 01553-003033

I hereby acknowledge & authenticate, every bit of information mentioned in this document is correct by all means.

Sincerely yours,

